I've made over $10 million as a personal
trainer, but if I was starting over in
2025, I'd do things very differently.
And this isn't about being rich, this
is about making a good living,
taking care of
your family,
and maybe the luxury of laying down on
your next flying
holiday.
So I'm going to show you everything in
this video that you would need to
go from zero to $1 million.
Now let's begin with stage number one.
This is going to be from zero to $5,000 a
month.
A lot of you won't want to hear this,
but you're going to do the majority of
this
in person. To the side here,
I'm going to set some benchmarks that
are very
important in stage one.
From zero to 100 posts, from zero to
100 hours, from zero to 10 clients,
from zero to 100 followers,
from zero to 100 email subscribers,
and from zero to 1,000 hours.
Now,
I know that can seem quite overwhelming.
I'm just going to go through each one of
those metrics and explain its importance
for stage one.
Let's begin with zero to 100 posts.
Even though you're new to this,
let's get out the gates.
Some important things to think about.
No one really cares about you.
They don't care about your lunch.
They don't care about your workout.
They care about themselves.
And in each person's life,
they have a set of problems.
Now you, in the line of work you are,
can help a lot of people with those using
your expertise, your experiences,
and your knowledge.
Then the fourth thing isn't actually any
of those.
It's the fact that we
are much more inclined to listen to a
stranger.
We are much more inclined to lift more
and heavier weights when people are
watching.
We are much more inclined to work to avoid
a loss, so when we financially
pay someone to do something,
we're more likely to do it.
So let's not forget number four.
Your first 100 posts are the hardest,
because
there's too many opportunities to give up.
Something bombs,
you give yourself all these excuses as to
why you could just start
another time. I don't care what platform,
Instagram, YouTube, TikTok, LinkedIn,
whatever. Just put your blinkers on.
Don't worry about post performance.
Don't worry about anything else apart from
doing those 100 posts.
The important thing here to remember
is that you get to set what success looks
like.
And success should not look like getting
mad engagement or clients from the
posts you've done out
or anything like that.
Success should look like actually posting.
One hundred posts should take about 100
days. Okay, let's move to the next one.
Zero to 100 hours. In front of you,
whether you're coaching people for
30-minute
slots, 45-minute slots, one-hour slots.
Again, blinkers on, road to 100 hours.
I don't care if you're offering sessions
out for half price, quarter price, doing
it for free. In stage one, we don't care.
Stage one, it's about raw volume,
raw experience.
I don't want you to worry about many
things apart from one hour down,
five hours
down, 10 hours down, 12 hours down.
Once you get to 100 hours, you
are quite literally 30 times better
at what you're doing in 100 hours.
It's your confidence, it's that your heart
rate's dropped, it's
that your speech has slowed down.
You're becoming familiar with your
environment and other coaches
and other people
in the gym and the equipment. The next
is zero to 10 clients.
What a lot of people don't tell you
is you can actually run a full book
and earn
incredible money with just 10 clients.
They would need to see you two to three
times a week, which to a very wealthy
client is fine because they want to come
to the gym and every single session, which
would be probably two or three a week,
they want their trainer there at the door.
They don't want to carry their program.
When I was charging a fortune back in
2016, I once had this client, she was a
banker,
and she was paying me $120 an hour for the
session.
She says,
"I want to do two a week." I said, "Cool,
but from what you've told me in
the consult,
I've actually given you a three-week
program.
So here are your options." I go,
"You do two sessions with me,
one on your own, or
you just pay me another $120 a week,
and for every single session,
I'm going to be
there." I said, "Yes, it
is another cost." I held the workout out
in front of her and I said,
"You will never have to touch this
if you just pay me
another $120 a week." Shook on it,
trained her three times a week,
$360 a week
from one client. Perfect world,
10 clients. It's very unlikely.
You're probably going to be looking at 20
or even 30 clients in the onset.
But again, zero to 10 clients.
If you're at nine clients,
every single day,
you talk to everyone in the gym floor,
you prospect every single person.
I don't care if the maintenance man comes
in with a ladder, you try and sell him
personal training. Don't actually try
and sell personal training.
Just talk to people.
Just ask them how they're getting on.
If you need anything, just let me know.
If you're not too pushy for quite a while,
"Like how much is personal training?"
You say,
"Don't discuss pricing on the floor,
Margaret. You know that.
Why don't we put in a little hour
and I can show you what I'm about,
you cheeky
girl." The next one,
nought to 100 followers.
If you're not there yet,
that's going to come.
But you might have done your 100 posts,
you might have done your 100 hours, you
might have done some other things.
You're going to keep pumping on social
media till you hit 100.
You might think that this
is the easy part.
Actually, nought to 100
is incredibly difficult. Nought to 1,000,
absolute slog.
Nought to 10K is probably half the battle.
10K to a million,
probably easier than zero to 10K.
The next is zero to 100 email subscribers.
In 2014,
when I started my first email list,
I thought, "What is email?
No one uses email anymore. Oh, emails
are boring." Trust me, and I mean trust
me, because within 12 months,
I've attributed over
$850,000 to just one email list. And if
emails didn't work, then in 2024, 2025,
I wouldn't have nearly made a million
dollars from a flipping single email list.
They still work.
Now,
some of your frequently asked questions in
stage one are going to be, do we
try and conquer all social media platforms
at the same time? Well, actually, yeah.
A piece of content is a digital asset,
and we're going to float that asset to the
internet,
and it's going to work for us in the
background.
On some platforms, it will do well,
some other platforms it may not.
If you're going to make a reel that's
specific to someone's problem,
why wouldn't
you put it in all places?
If it's a portrait 58-second reel, YouTube
Shorts, LinkedIn, Facebook, TikTok,
Twitter, Instagram.
Is there a platform that--
Just do it yourself.
It's like 10 seconds per platform.
One of those little bloody digital assets,
in time, will go bloody viral,
grow your email list by 300 people,
and bag you four clients that then pay you
$1,000 each.
So it's four grand to put it on the
platform.
Would you do it for that? Yeah. Well,
shut up then.
When do you start building an email list?
As soon as possible.
There are websites out there like AWeber,
A-W-E-B-E-R.
You can create a little sign-up form,
and you can start collecting emails
straight
away. Now,
the email list thing can seem very
daunting, so what I've actually done
is in the description,
I've created a free lead magnet course,
which teaches you
what you would say
and offer people for their email address.
It's completely free.
There are no catches, whatever.
I created it because so many of your lead
magnets
are shit.
The third frequently asked question
that I always get is: do you pick a
niche? When I see people going,
"I help 22 to 40-year-old men
get in the best shape of their life." Shut
up. No, you don't.
Because if someone comes along at 21 with
a Bugatti, you'll train him.
And if he's 50, and he's a millionaire,
you'll train him.
So take the age groups out.
When it comes to gender,
unless you're teaching
pre/postnatal,
gender isn't the biggest thing either.
For most of you,
rather than trying to niche down on a
person and try to be seen by
them, which I'm not going to lie,
you look pathetic all the time, and you've
obviously read an Alex Hormozi book,
and you're going,
"But Alex Hormozi says that
I should only work with left-handed
people." Yeah, you mean Alex Hormozi,
who grew
his socials to fucking millions,
then sold hundreds and thousands of
books to quite literally anyone
that has a business.
You're listening to niching from the one
person whose niche is everyone.
Nice one. You don't niche on the person,
you niche on the problem.
Because if the problem is fat loss,
the advice is the same to Tracy, to
Sam, to Dave, to John, to the student,
to the nurse, to the fucking mum of
six kids. It's the same.
So niche on the problem and solve the
problem in your content. Don't try
and say, "I work with busy men that are
professionals who are..." You're just
trying to say you work with rich men.
But guess what? It's bollocks,
and people see straight through it.
So don't try and niche down to a specific
person. Have an avatar in mind.
Where is the person? Where do they live?
What do they do for a job?
What are their struggles?
What solution would help them?
What plan could you put in place?
What lead magnet would be of interest to
them?
But you're going to end up like
that lady online who goes, "Lesbians,
if you're
looking to lose fat." Like rug munching
has a different type of caloric equation
to people that are heterosexual.
You're doing our heads in.
And you're probably thinking,
what about training online? Well,
shut your mouth.
We're getting there. The stage is one.
Let's move over to stage two.
Then we get to stage two, which
is getting from 5K to 20K.
And unfortunately,
your life goes from working in a gym
and counting reps and sets
to working a lot behind a laptop
and a computer.
And the truth is,
soon you'll be running a tech business
that provides
programs for people. So you
are going to need a good MacBook,
a good computer, and
in time, a camera like that.
And before you know it,
you're going to be in a room
like me, surrounded by tripods,
top-down camera setups.
I've got props over here from various
videos.
At first,
every time you get a canceled client,
you should be on your laptop.
At stage one, client cancels,
you're going around the gym floor picking
up another
client. At stage two,
the best use of your time
is to now open your laptop, serve
your existing clients,
and do some online digital marketing.
Stage two is about forcing your hand to
leave the gym floor.
When it's your lunch break,
you're getting food,
and you're sat at your laptop.
In the afternoons, ultimately,
you want to turn
that into your online time.
Think about when you do a workout,
you always want to do the hardest part
first.
So you always get people to train legs
first in a workout.
You never get someone to come in
and do bicep curls
and then finish with squats.
You do the hardest part first.
The same goes with personal training.
Being with people face to face
is the difficult part.
Opening your laptop,
getting a cup of coffee from Waitrose,
that's the easy part.
Now,
I'm going to take you back to a quick
story.
I was working in a gym called Absolutely
Fitness in Bracknell, when I get an email
from a guy called Cliff,
and he says he wants to train with me.
I go, "Sweet, come in.
Let's do a consult." He goes, "James,
I live in Dubai." I
went, "Mate,
that's a long way to come for a consult."
He goes, "Just train me
online." I go, "I don't do that." He goes,
"We'll figure it out." So kind of said
to him, "Okay, what do you need?" He goes,
"I need to lose weight, and I need to
train." I was like, "Yeah,
do you know what?
We could probably do this remote." Now,
everyone out there has got their different
ideas of what delivering to a client looks
like.
And straight away,
you're thinking super expensive training
apps, integrations,
APIs. I'll be honest with you.
The majority of people just want a program
to follow
and someone that gives a shit.
And you can create that within a day.
Now, me personally,
I never did check-in calls,
never did weekly check-ins, never
did monthly check-ins.
The thought of getting on the phone with
anyone for an hour
just, I loathe it. I just don't like it.
So I ended up attracting a load of clients
that didn't particularly need to be
spoken to. "Hey, Trish, how are you?
How did you get on this week?
Fantastic." I just WhatsApp me.
WhatsApp for desktop.
It's how I communicate with my friends.
It's how I communicate with my family.
It's how I communicate with my online
clients.
What I did was, as soon as
that first payment came in on Stripe
or PayPal, I would
change their name on WhatsApp
and put in bold capital letters,
ONLINE CLIENT.
So when Tracy joined, ONLINE CLIENT.
And then the second
that their payment's finished,
I delete that out their name.
Then anytime I got a WhatsApp notification
from someone that said online client, I
was like, "This person is paying me.
I'm going to get back to it as soon as
physically possible." I would rather have
had little drips and drabs of
communication via messages on WhatsApp
every day than
to ghost my client for six days to then
speak to them for an hour on a Friday.
You might think you're delivering extra
value with that, but the perfect clients
are going to be wealthy.
They're going to be business owners.
They're going to be busy people.
They don't want to sit on the phone with
an hour
with someone who's their coach.
They just don't.
Give them a good program,
rotate it frequently,
ask them on a weekly basis what
they like, what they don't like,
change it accordingly.
Again,
the program has to be a mixture of what
they love and what they need.
You can't make it just too much what they
need, or they won't love it.
And you can't make it just too much what
they love, or it won't work.
Also, another little bonus
that could help is whenever I took on a
client, I'd make
them send a video to me. I'd make them go,
"Hi, James. My name's Trisha.
I'm looking to lose weight.
I'm very excited to work with you." Now,
the video was
so that I could get an understanding for
what that person was like.
Because sometimes people
are timid as shit. They're like, "Hi,
James.
I'm not really that confident."
Straight away,
I knew Trisha's going nowhere near a squat
rack.
She's going to be doing goblet squats in
the functional training room.
She's going to be doing rear foot elevated
split squats.
I also know that in the goblet squats I
was to give her,
I'd tell her to do it with
a kettlebell, not a dumbbell, because
if she's using a 12-kilogram dumbbell for
a
goblet squat,
she's going to have to go into the
scariest part of the gym and fight
off men that are doing bicep curls with
it.
So much can be done with a client,
just giving a shit, checking in with them,
messaging them, rotating their program.
It's all you really need to be a good
online coach.
Good pricing point start for that
is to charge a week what you would charge
in
person. Now, you will need a landing page.
You will need a menu.
You will need something for people to go
to through your marketing sequence.
Now, in a perfect world,
how I would do it is have socials.
Social media is number one job.
Get email addresses.
Email addresses run some kind of email
marketing campaign to then get them to a
landing page. Again,
if you don't know how to run an email
marketing campaign, I'm
actually going to put a bundle in the
description to this video, which gives you
three courses from me for just over the
price of one.
It's an email marketing course,
a content creation course,
and a PT course.
I think it's like 100
and something dollars.
It's a fucking steal.
And again, no offense.
Download the invoice
that you get from purchasing it and
just put it against your expenses.
If you pay gym rent, this goes with it.
When you buyBuy a camera,
this goes with it.
When you buy a computer,
That doesn't mean it's free.
It reduces the profitability of your
business,
and reducing the profitability of
your business means you pay less tax.
It also means you have less money,
but it means it's cost-efficient.
You should not be buying things for your
business, your business should.
And if you haven't got that sorted out,
get a flipping accountant.
So the email marketing will push people to
a landing page.
A landing page is a website just designed
for people to buy.
Now, on that landing page,
it's like a menu.
Your services,
what your clients have to say,
how much you charge.
Some little snakes out there will tell you
to hide your pricing. Don't do that.
Imagine going to a restaurant
that didn't show you prices till you got
there.
Snakey. You wouldn't do it in a hotel,
don't do it in other places.
Don't overcomplicate it. Again,
there's actually a free resource in the
description
to this on highly converting landing page.
You click on that,
I'll actually send you a template how to
do that for free as
well. So,
so far you've got two courses for free
and a PT bundle.
It's quite a lot of value
if you end up giving me your money.
So the landing page, we want a headline,
a promise, a subheading, then we want a
video called a VSL, which
is you just saying,
"Welcome to my online coaching
program.
I put this together to solve this problem,
this problem, this problem for
people that have this problem,
this problem, this problem.
The way it works is this, this, this."
And a very rough structure of this is what
it is, why they need it, what they get,
why to trust you, how to pay.
And I know that can seem like I said
that quite quick, but again,
it's in the free
resource in the description. Now,
one thing to make clear is there
are a lot of
other gurus online doing similar things to
me.
Have many of them had a PT business of the
same size of mine? Not really.
Because I'm in a funny place.
I've made good money with a fitness app,
but
not generational wealth.
I'm in the happy medium.
Everyone who makes more than me has loads
of staff, loads of moving parts, HR
departments and all that. I don't.
It's me, Declan's editor,
and I've got my business partner, James,
for the fitness
app. We've got our coaches who
are fantastic, but we keep it lean.
So if you want to have a massive business
with 100 staff, you would probably just
hire someone to do your email marketing,
do your landing pages, do your content for
you. You'd be perfect for my mentorship
if you want to do it yourself.
Because the email marketing department
is me.
The content creation department is me.
The HR department is me.
So the other gurus online will tell you to
charge huge amounts up
front,
that people need to commit to 12-week
periods, or 16-week periods, or six
months up front,
and they're doing this in a bad way.
So let's say your name's John,
you're in the UK, you're making
£1,500 a month.
You're going to start working with some
gurus who are going to say,
"John,
you need to get commitment from your
clients.
You're going to charge them for four
months up front, full commitment.
They need to commit.
You get them on the phone, John,
and you don't get off till
you've got the sale." Don't know why they
talk like that, but that's what they're
like. Everyone's like,
"You need sales calls." You don't.
"You need commitment." You don't.
"You need to book a..."
And what they do is they pretty much get
all your revenue
for the next four months
and get you to close it this week.
So then that guru can go,
"See John over here? He's making...
What were you making, John?
£1,500 a month.
What'd you make last month, John?
22 grand. Do you hear that?
22 grand John just made because of me, his
business guru." But it wasn't 22 grand for
the month.
It was 22 grand for the next flipping five
months.
Then John thinks he's rich all of a
sudden,
spends loads of money he hasn't got,
then has to go back into another marketing
cycle and he's like, "Where's all my
money next week?" Well, John,
you took all of the revenue from all the
leads in one
go. Anyway,
they do it so it looks good to the guru.
For you guys, as a PT,
if you had a client who walked in
and said, "Can I pay you
£50 a week?" You go, "Yeah,
it's fine." You wouldn't say, "No,
I need a commitment
of 10 weeks up." You go,
"Just bring in the money every week,
mate." That's the
same for your online.
If you can get people to pay a recurring
cashflow, first of
all, it reduces the barrier to entry.
Most of you bastards
that join my mentorship after this video,
you're going to jump
on the split pay option because it's not
even the cost, it's that you don't want to
give all the money up front.
You'd rather pay it in certain amounts
with Klarna or
PayPal split in four, whatever it is.
It's a cashflow thing.
The same reason most people don't pay for
Netflix on annual, they pay for it
monthly. It's a cashflow thing.
So you need to make sure that you
are giving your
audience as many options as possible.
And weekly is fine.
First of all, the barrier to entry
is very small.
Second of all, if they don't like it
and you have to refund them,
it won't break
your heart. Because
if they've paid three months in one go,
and then you have to
refund them because they hate your product
and hate you, which happens, it's going
to break your heart
and it's going to ruin your day.
Third thing, knowing that every client
is on a one-week cycle will keep
you invested and on top of the ball with
managing them and keeping them
happy. Most the advice
that gurus give you
is with their own interests in heart.
Now, stage two, this
is how it's going to work.
You've got demand on the gym floor,
or you wouldn't be in stage two.
You've got demand online that's building
because your social media's growing, your
email marketing list is growing.
Your email marketing list should be about
20% of
your total amount of followers.
And because of this demand,
you can now segment
most your clients to the morning.
So now you should open your diary from
6:00 a.m.
till midday. That's when you PT.
Maybe a 1:00 p.m., maybe a 2:00 p.m., but
everything after
that should be online only.
And now the beauty
is you've got one foot in in-person,
one foot online.
So in the morning, film your clients.
When they hit a breakthrough,
like 10 kilograms lost,
get a picture of them holding
a 10K plate.
You stand in the picture with them.
Get them to do lifts.
Talk about your client's bit.
Not the only thing in the content because
no one
cares. Show Janice strengths progression.
Show Dave's weight loss.
Then you create content on calories,
on macros, whatever it is you want to talk
about as a PT. Socials grow,
email list grows.
Email marketing goes out.
Online clients onboarded.
Online clients give good feedback.
Market the online feedback back into
content. Suddenly the email list grows.
You're creating this self-perpetuating
cycle of happy customers, new business,
happy customers, new business.
But the beauty is when you're in person,
you charge for an hour,
you have to give them an hour.
With online,
you smash enough energy drinks,
you can service your clients in
really short periods of time.
Some days a client will ask you two things
and you
will service them in six minutes.
You'll spend five minutes on their
program,
changing a few of it.
Front foot elevated split squat to rear
foot elevated split
squat. It's not rocket science.
And then next thing you know you've got an
hour's
wages to spend 20 minutes on someone.
You've just tripled your hourly rate.
And this is how you decouple your time
from your income.
And you can start to scale in a world
where you work harder, you earn more money
without having to give over more time.
Now,
as you're coming to the end of stage two,
there are a few things to consider.
One, to create a product.
I'll show you my own suite of products in
a
second. Another thing
is to consider a pivot.
Could be writing a book,
creating a course, whatever it is.
I got to a point in my PT business where
on my own I was making about
£200,000 a year, which is crazy.
I had what?
65 clients paying... No,
I had 72 clients paying 75 a week.
72 clients, 65 a week. £4,680
a week times 52. Yeah, I
was doing quarter of a million pounds.
When was this? Where's all
that money gone?
If in the very early stages of 2017 I
was earning
£243,000, what is
that in today's money with inflation?
That's how old I am.
I've got to count inflation in.
£326,000 in today's money. Wow. Why did I
ever... Where is that money? Where is
that money? Where is that money?
Anyway, that was on my own.
But then I had to pivot, productize.
I had to go to stage three.
That's what I'm saying.
So we're going to get into stage three
now. Let's go have a look.
So my coaching app
is called Afford Worldwide Coaching.
Let's call it the AWC.
So suddenly we had to change from coaching
as a service to creating a product.
There are many ways that you can use it.
We decided to have a seven-day free trial,
which gives people full access to the
app. Now within that,
we give them a program which is at a cost.
We pay our coach to provide that program.
Now from here, we're at a loss,
so it's time to try and get a make
up for that loss.
So there's several membership tiers
that we try and put
people onto. The ultimate goal
that we want them to go onto is premium.
Now, premium is 14 pounds per week,
and it includes a coach to provide
a program, someone to talk to,
full access to the app, and the community.
So we're trying to compete with personal
training at a much cheaper cost.
We do this at 53 pounds a month,
which again, if you're in London,
that's what
you'd pay for a single PT session.
But the main way we try
and promote this is in a
block for four months at 170 pounds.
And the main way we build revenue every
few months is to package the premium
into a block,
which goes into our challenge.
Most of our challenges are 12 weeks,
but we also have a six week.
There have been times
that we've supported the entire business
just on 12-week
challenges using those revenue blocks
and people joining.
Sometimes you get several thousand people
joining a challenge.
As a prize money,
we give out about $10,000.
The reason that I'm putting this in pounds
is the majority of you are English.
Now, the premium plan
is supported by our coaches.
Our coaches are contractors.
We pay them per program so they can have
their own jobs, their own worlds, their
own clients, whatever. Finding coaches
is actually very easy.
Whenever we put feelers out, there
are so many coaches out there with no
work.
So really,
because the hard part isn't coaching.
What I want you to think about
is the hard part here
is winning over clients
through marketing. So
when you can get good at winning over
clients through
marketing,
you get access to running a pretty
scalable business.
The reason my coaches work for me, I hope,
is they like the mission that I'm on,
but also they just can't be bothered to
market and win over new business.
They would rather just open their laptop
and help people for a living.
Now,
not everyone is going to go from a
seven-day trial straight into premium,
even
at a good rate.
So let's say after seven days,
no purchase is made.
We then will float something called the
starter plan.
Now, the starter plan
is 10 pounds per month, and what we do
is we actually give
them access to the program
that they got on the trial.
So straight away,
that's at no extra cost to us,
and they can continue to use that.
And whenever they want,
they can buy a one-off plan for 15 pounds.
So if they want to do four, six,
eight weeks,
this still works out incredibly
affordable compared to other traditional
plans on the Internet.
They can ride this for as long as they
want,
and they can also buy a pass into the
challenge.
The reason we don't let them join for free
is just so that the
judging component of the challenge
is quite resource heavy.
So we still need to pay people to help
with the judging.
When you've got 3,000 people in a
challenge, it takes a very long time.
So you need to pay people for their time
to go through all the applications.
At the moment,
we've probably got about 3,500 people on
starter and that revenue
adds up. Now,
some people will go onto premium
and we can't expect these people to
be with us forever.
They'll do a few challenges.
I probably say the average person does
probably two challenges.
Then when these guys have finished,
they come back around to a plan called
bridging. And bridging
is five pounds a month.
Now, the reason bridging
is half the cost of starter
is they've already been in
premium.
They've already been contributing to our
ecosystem, paying our coaches.
And the reason we call it bridging
is some of them might just want to go down
to
this plan for a while.
They might go on holiday,
be a training break, injury,
whatever it is.
Or some of them will just want to use the
challenges.
They've already got their program,
they've already used the coach,
they've already
learnt and upskilled
and got everything
that they need to from the coach so they
can just keep trickling along with their
plans.
And sometimes for our members
that have been with us for years,
they might have
eight to ten programs.
So they can go down to five pounds a month
and just keep
cycling through the programs
that we've made for them before.
And then recently we added premium plus,
where we've added a dietician.
Now, this one is 35 pounds a week
and that's become what you would consider
a high
ticket offer for our ecosystem anyway,
where people can join, not just get a
program, work with a dietician. And
if you were going to source a personal
trainer
and a dietician together,
it'd be a lot more expensive than 35
pounds.
So the beauty of this,
the productization of this is my job,
my sole
purpose is to just bring people onto the
trial.
Once people are on the trial,
we hit like a 15% conversion rate for them
going on a
paid plan. Once they go to premium,
they can end up on bridging.
If they don't take the premium,
they can go onto starter.
And if some people need specialist
attention, they can go to plus.
And every few weeks we'll do a revenue
drive through promoting the challenge.
This is stage three. This
is how you turn a service of counting reps
in the gym
into a product. And your position in
that product can just be sending traffic
to
the website. Now, stage four,
hitting 100K a month.
Going from stage three to stage four
is where things get pretty interesting.
For a lot of fitness businesses,
it's hard to earn 100K a month,
especially when your costs aren't massive.
And stage four is where you probably need
to consider a pivot into B2B,
business to business. Now,
this can seem like a really slimy
and sneaky move, but
I'll explain something.
For stage three to work,
you have to be very good at
landing pages, conversions,
email marketing, and content creation.
If you weren't,
you shouldn't have made it to stage three.
And once you've operated
and run a business where you become an
expert at sending
traffic to a website,
it makes sense to productize the process
of how you got there
in the first place.
What I want you to consider is if you
are going to make it to
stage three and do well there,
you're going to trailblaze and people
are going to
want to follow you.
Whether you're in fitness,
maybe even in another adjacent
industry, physio or whatever.
If you do it well enough, other people
are going to
want to know how you did it.
And I don't think there's anything wrong
with showing
people the information of how you did it.
There's plenty enough clients to go
around.
So I'm going to quickly show you my
ecosystem because if your B2C goes well
enough,
this could be you in a few years.
I never thought I'd have a B2B business.
But if you're going to do well as you want
to, this is going to be a transition
that's going to occur.
So we've got the business mentorship.
So, so far already in the description,
there's a lead magnet for how to
get higher conversions on your landing
page and there's lead magnet mastery.
These things are free and people
are going to get a lot of value from
these.
And in time, if people enjoy these,
they could buy into my IP only plan.
Now, this isn't released yet,
but about three days ago, I had to shut no
entry into my business mentorship.
There's just too many people in there.
And although the Discord
is a great place for people to chat,
work together, get
critiques, whatever,
there's still quite a large percentage of
people that don't
particularly like or want to use the
Discord.
So we're going to put a big discount on
the business mentorship and call it IP
only.
We're going to turn it from a service to a
product.
Exactly what we did in stage three.
I think this is going to be over $1,000
discounted.
Now,
even though there won't be a link to this
in the description, I urge you to
get these two because
if you download these two,
or at least sign up to them, you
will get to see the process
that I put you through to convert you.
And this is going to be the exact same
thing that you're going to do in your
fitness business to win over new business.
You're going to give them something for
free to nurture them into buying your
product. Now,
if you think of this as your coaching,
sometimes people aren't ready
to buy in.
And when you get to stage three,
you're going to need to create some
products. So for me,
I've created Short Form Content Mastery.
We sell about 10 of those a day.
I created an email marketing course called
Send
Emails, Get Paid.
And I created another course called the PT
Starter Kit.
Now, good news for you guys today
is these have been bundled There's an
offer using
the link. So if you click on that, again,
once you buy the bundle, you're probably
going to get an offer for OPO. Inside OPO,
you get Chatbot & Chill,
Your Bio Sucks, Mentorship 2.0,
and all new courses.
So my job on YouTube right now for
business mentorship is to convert
things that are free, but also things
that are paid.
Some people will get the free stuff,
end up getting paid.
Some people will pay for stuff,
Once I've got them here,
I now give them to a suite of absolutely
everything.
And anything new
that I add will go to these people in
here.
So this is the main offering. This
is what your coaching service would be.
This could be some programs
that you might sell, maybe around squat,
maybe around
deadlifts, maybe around nutrition,
maybe about recipes, whatever it is.
Then this stuff might be a training
planner. It might be recipes.
It could be a calorie calculator.
Whatever it is.
You're going to have an ecosystem of
things that are free, things that are low
ticket, things that are higher ticket,
and they're all going to feed each other.
I'm now going to go through a big
promotion for these things.
And whilst the mentorship shut down,
I'm going in on creating a full YouTube
course
called the Silver Play Button, which
is going to teach you guys how to get your
Silver Play Button on YouTube by getting
100,000 subscribers.
When you get to level three and
when you get to level four,
it's imperative that
you realize that you need to build an
ecosystem that feeds everything.
Then even if we get rid of this for now.
Now, the important thing here
is to explain that once you get good at
one business,
you can get good at all businesses.
The same way that we've now got Nutonic to
over $20 million valuation.
It's this exact step.
You build your social media, YouTube,
Instagram, Facebook,
TikTok, all of it.
You collect email addresses,
landing pages,
sales. Whether Nutonic,
whether my business mentorship,
whether my coaching app, it
is all the same. And there
are just little things that
are going to help from
socials to emails. ManyChat,
which I made a course, Chatbot &
Chill. Emails to the landing page,
Send Emails Get Paid.
Landing pages to sales,
the High Converting Landing Page course.
How to get better on socials,
Short-Form Content Mastery.
Every single course I make
is about making you better at this funnel.
And now, the PT bundle
that I put in the link
is going to help you with all of
these things for your fitness business.
But the beauty is, your next business
is going to be the one that makes you the
most money. Probably
when you sidestep from fitness in 5 to 10
years, which will
feel like a bit of a weird thing to think
about now, because I never thought I'd
have a drinks business.
Gymshark started off selling vests.
They made their billions in leggings.
Grenade started off with a pre-workout,
ends up having the most popular protein
bar
in the world.
Adam Sullivan made millions from being a
PT, he's probably going to
make more from his creatine gummies.
What I'm selling is how to master this.
This could take years.
This could take months.
These can happen soon.
I would love to stand here
and tell you that there's a secret way
or that there's a
shortcut or a hack
or a blueprint to follow.
But you actually just need to get really
good at loads of different things.
Even in jujitsu,
you need to get good at arm bars,
leg locks, takedowns, guards,
whatever.
There's so many components to get good at
to get your black belt.
You need to do the same. I'm a coach.
I've taught people for years.
The world of fitness,
the world of business
is very much the same.
There's one more thing I need to say.
Being a personal trainer is a very,
very difficult job. It is not
that glamorous.
It has very long days,
and only the fittest survive,
pardon the pun.
If you can dominate
and create a massive
and profitable fitness business, you can
literally go into any other business.
And also, think about this.
The qualities of a coach
is assessing people's problems,
giving them a
simplified plan of action
that they can follow to save time, energy,
and effort.
I did that for years on the gym.
I'm now probably better at it in business
than I
ever was in the world of fitness.
So whether you're looking to go from zero
to
stage one, one to stage two,
two to stage three, three to stage four,
I have years
of experience in every single one.
And I'm currently productizing every
single component of it,
just like I did in the
world of fitness.
And I'm pretty good at that, too.
So you shouldn't just consider buying my
paid program with the links in the
description because it could help you a
tremendous amount, or that it's a business
expense. I'll be honest with you
and close with this.
I've hired mentors
and experts across the years to help me in
different domains.
They didn't just teach me stuff.
They inspired me so
that I could do it myself when
I got to that level. Ed Lawrence,
Paul Moore, even Phil Learney.
You may not know some of those names.
I didn't copy them. I hired them.
And I went from their student to becoming
one of their peers.
And that's the potential for you.
Like I said,
the link's in the description.
I hope you found that video helpful.
If you didn't find
that video enough to click on the links
and buy anything, then
you should check out this one here,
because YouTube reckons
that you'll enjoy this
one just as much as you enjoyed that one.
Bye-bye.